我们走运了
We are so in luck!
房东说这些好东西都可以给我们
Treeger said we could have all this cool stuff!
等一下
Wait right there.
不行，我要划走了
Oh,no. I'm paddling away.
真的？ 这些生锈的垃圾不要钱？
Really? We got all this rusty crap for free?
还有一堆泡泡棉 有些完全没挤过
This and a bunch of bubble wrap. And some of it is not even popped.
我们真是穷苦的白人吗？
Could we be more white trash?
本集播出：“爱的手铐”
The One with the Cuffs
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯
丽莎库卓
麦特勒布兰
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
我真是绝望透了
How desperate am l?
幸好钱德不在，谁也惨不过他
Good thing Chandler's not here. He always wins at this game.
我刚答应帮我妈办宴会
I just told my mom I'd cater her party.
为什么？
-How come?
因为我需要钱
-I need the money.
而且这样正好可以抛开 最后一丝自尊
It'd be a great way to get rid of that last smidgen of self-respect.
别这样，这是好事啊
I think this is a good thing.
要不是觉得你行，妈不会找你
Mom wouldn't have hired you if you weren't good.
你不必替她说话，她听不到
You don't have to stick up for her. She can't hear you.
你们有果汁吗？
Do you have any juice?
只有腌黄瓜汁
Just pickle.
瑞秋，说来好笑 我昨天在路上遇见乔安娜
Funny story. I bumped into Joanna yesterday.
我的上司乔安娜？一定很尴尬
My boss,Joanna? That must have been awkward.
事实上她找我一起去喝酒
Actually,she asked me if I wanted a drink.
你没有答应吧？
You didn't say yes to that,did you?
没有
No,No
瑞秋
Hello,Rachel.
一开始没答应
Well,not at first.
她在这里干什么？
What is she doing here?
我不懂 你上次跟她约会时说她很无聊
Last time you went out with her you said she was a dud!
我太快下定论了 这次我们进展到下一个阶段
I judged her too quickly. This time,we took it to the next level.
我上次差点被炒鱿鱼 你马上给我做个了结
Last time I almost got fired. You must end it. You must end it now.
这可不是每天都有的事
It's not an everyday occurrence!
通常我都一个人睡
Usually I'm in there by myself.
钱德！答应我…
Promise.
瑞秋，你快迟到了吧？ 没有啊
-Rachel,aren't you running late? -No
有，你还要帮我买焙果 好
-You are if you pick me up a bagel. -Okay.
钱德，答应我跟她分手
Promise you will end this now.
好，我会跟她分手 谢谢
-I promise. I'll end it. -Thank you.
不过我的牺牲很大
I hope you know what I'm giving up.
她可不只是你的上司，懂吗？
She's not just the boss in your office. You know what I mean?
对不起，我懂他的意思
Sorry. I knew what he meant.
雇工忙得怎样？
How's the hired help?
很顺利，乳酪火腿馅饼快好了
Doing great. Quiches are coming along.
这是什么？蓝色指甲油？
What's this? Blue nail polish?
对，我觉得很好看
I thought it was cute.
当我们找到你外婆时她的指甲就是这个颜色
It's what your grandmother's hands looked like when we found her.
我问你一个问题
Let me ask you a question.
你为什么雇我？
Why did you hire me?
理查一直说他的派对餐点很棒
Richard raved about the food at his party...
但你当时在跟他上床
...but you were sleeping with him.
后来我听说 那场同志婚礼的菜很好
Then I heard the food at that lesbian wedding was nice.
你应该没跟那些人上床吧
I assume you didn't sleep with anyone there.
否则起码很特别
At least that would be something.
天哪！你听到了吗？
Oh,my God! Did you hear that?
她是觉得我很行才雇我
She hired me because she thinks I'm good.
我没听到这个
I didn't hear that.
她不是在可怜我
She didn't hire me out of pity.
不是想在朋友面前刁难我 她是真的觉得我行
It wasn't so she could pick on me. She actually thinks I'm good.
还有，如果你是同志就太酷了
And hey,it's cool if you're a lesbian.
午安，你是这里的家长吗？
Good afternoon. Are you the decision-maker of the house?
你目前拥有一套百科全书吗？
Do you currently own a set of encyclopedias?
没有 不过分类广告上什么都有
No,but try the classifieds. People sell everything in there.
我不是要买，我是要卖
Actually,I'm not buying. I'm selling.
我问你一个问题
Let me ask you one question.
你是否曾在朋友们聊天时
Do your friends ever have a conversation...
只能跟着点头 却搞不懂他们在说什么？
...and you just nod along,not sure what they're talking about?
告诉你，这根本是违宪 没错
I'm telling you,it's totally unconstitutional.
我觉得他应该得诺贝尔奖
I think he deserves a Nobel Prize.
才怪
No
很像阿尔冈昆族（印第安部族）小孩的桌子
It was like the Algonquin kids' table.
抱歉，对不起
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
你发了大约2分半钟的呆
You haven't said anything for about two minutes.
你到底有没有兴趣？
Are you at all interested?
有…请进
Come on in.
怪了 什么？
-That's weird. -What?
你的假指甲
Your nails.
我知道，我带了假指甲怕咬指甲被我妈唠叨
I wore fake ones so my mom wouldn't give me grief about biting them.
我是说你现在只有九个指甲
I meant,it's weird that you only have nine now.
天哪
Oh,my God!
等一下
Wait a minute.
我之前要烤…
I had them when I put
天哪，在馅饼里面
Oh,my God! It's in the quiche!
完了！ 好，不要慌
-Oh,my God! -Okay,don't panic.
我去帮你买一组新指甲
I'll go buy you a new set of nails.
没有人会知道，你还是很美
No one will know,and you'll look great!
噢，你是怕他们会吃到
It's because they're going to eat That's the problem.
女儿，别咬指甲
Honey,don't bite your nails.
你别生气
Please don't freak out.
不过某个馅饼里有一片假指甲
There's a blue fingernail in one of the quiche cups.
而且无从找起
And there's no way to know which one.
找到的人可以中大奖
And whoever finds it wins the prize!
我不会生气
I'm not freaking out.
你在笑什么？ 没事，你爸输我5块钱
-Why are you laughing? -Now your father owes me $5.
你赌我会掉指甲？
You bet I'd lose a nail?
别傻了 我只是赌我会用上这个
Don't be silly. I just bet that I'd need these.
冷冻意大利面？
Frozen lasagnas?
你赌我会搞砸？
You bet that I'd screw up?
你还说什么我很行…
All that stuff about how I was good
不，那都是真的
No,that was all true.
这只是怕你太莫妮卡了
This was just in case you "pulled a Monica."
你答应心理医生不再这么说
You promised Dr. Weinberg you'd never use that phrase.
拜托，有点幽默感嘛
Come on. Have a sense of humor.
你总是不懂得自嘲
You're never able to laugh at yourself.
是啊
That's right.
我妈对我没信心，好好笑喔
My mom has no faith in me! That's hilarious!
哪里好笑？
I don't get it.
不，我对你有信心
No. I have faith.
不，你有的是意大利面
No. You have lasagnas!
毁掉的馅饼好了
The ruined quiches are ready!
我们不该这么做 好
-I really don't think we should be doing this. -Okay.
这种感觉不像是分手
It just doesn't feel like we're breaking up.
是分手啊，我好伤心喔
No,we are. I'm sad.
好吧
Okey
可以等到明天吗？好吧
Can you wait till tomorrow? All right.
不敢相信
Unbelievable!
谢谢
Thanks.
不是，我得去见我的老板 好
That was my boss. I have to go.
你干什么？
What are you doing?
穿衣服 为什么？
-I'm getting dressed. -Why?
光着屁股走在路上会被扔东西
When I walk outside naked,people throw garbage.
等一下，给你看个东西
Wait. I want to show you something.
什么东西？
What is it?
别人送的一个小道具
Just a little gag gift somebody gave me.
把手合在一起
Put your hands together.
你又不是我的老板
You're not the boss of me.
你是
Yeah,you are.
火辣啊
Saucy!
我马上回来
I'll be back in two minutes.
你要这样把我挂着？
You're going to leave me like this?
知道你在等我 感觉很令人兴奋
Knowing you're here waiting for me. I think it's exciting,don't you?
好，但要是你不马上回来…
If you don't come back soon...
我也不能怎么样
...there's pretty much nothing I can do about it!
我帮你带了杏仁饼回来
I brought you back a macaroon.
很好，我会把它帖在屁股上
Great. I'll keep it in my butt with your nose.
奇怪，她把门锁上了
That's weird. She locked the door.
你知道为什么？ 里面有圣诞奖金名单
You know why? She's got the bonus list in there.
我早上看到她在打
I saw her working on it today.
好，你可别说出去
Swear you won't tell.
马克离职时给了我一把钥匙
When Mark left,he gave me a key to her office.
你想看名单吗？ 想
You want to see the list?
你好吗？
How are you?
喂，乔安娜…
Hello,Joanna…
…的办公室
office.
对不起，我还要一阵子
I'm sorry. I'll be a little longer.
多久？ 2个小时，我急死了
-How little? -A couple hours.
一点也不好玩，马上给我回来
This isn't funny. Get back here now!
我没办法 为什么？
-I can't! -Why not?
我在我老板的车上
I'm in my boss' car.
什么？ 进隧道了
-What? -Tunnel!
干什么？
What?
瑞秋，你能进来一下吗？
Rachel,could I see you for a moment?
好，现在是这样
Okay,here's the situation.
手铐的钥匙挂在门上
The keys to the cuffs are on the door.
你能不能行行好
Could you be a doll...
拿了钥匙冲过来帮我解套？
...and grab them and scoot on over here and unlock me?
题外话：好漂亮的套装
And on a totally separate subject,that's a lovely pantsuit.
你答应要跟她分手的
You promised you would break up with her.
我跟她分手啦 只不过她分得很狂野
I did break up with her! She just took it really,really well!
你都没想过 这样会破坏我的事业？
Jeopardizing my career never entered your mind?
我想过啊
It did enter my mind.
但后来的事让这个念头飞了
But then something happened that made it shoot right out.
你害自己被铐住，就自己脱困
You got yourself into those cuffs,you get yourself out.
不，我没办法自己脱困
I can't get myself right out of them.
你把我跟“不可思议的钱德”搞混了
You must have me confused with the "Amazing Chandler"!
帮我解开，她可能要去很久 我好冷，而且…
Unlock me! She could be gone for hours,and I'm cold and....
钱德！好，够了
All right! This is it!
不准你再见她
Never see her again.
永远
Never!
不准再进这个办公室
-Never come in here again.
好
-Fine!
把随身听还给我 我…
Give me back my Walkman!
我没借过
I never borrowed it.
那就是我弄丢了，买一台给我
Then I lost it. Buy me one!
没问题，快解开吧，太好了
You got it! Here we go! Come on. This is great!
会痛吗？
Does it hurt?
不，我只是看别人解开铐子时都会啊一声
No,I always see guys do this when handcuffs are taken off.
亲爱的裤子
Hello,sweet pants!
慢着！你要怎么跟乔安娜说？
Wait! What will you tell Joanna?
说什么？
About what?
她看你走了会知道是我放的 我会被解雇
She'll see you're gone and know I let you out,and I'll get fired!
我会撒谎，我最会撒谎了
I'll tell a lie! I'm good at lying!
我的确借了你的随身听
I actually did borrow your Walkman!
行不通的，她会知道我有钥匙
She'll know I have a key to her office.
我得把你铐回去
I've got to lock you back up.
你别想
I don't think so.
这样好多了
This is much better.
这个人很有意思
Here's somebody interesting.
你对梵高（画家）认识多少？
What do you know about Van Gogh?
他割掉自己的耳朵 还有呢？
-He cut off his ear. -And?
没了
I'm out.
这是他画的
He painted that.
不赖嘛
That's pretty nice.
我以为他割掉耳朵是因为自己画不好
I thought he cut off his ear because he sucked.
还有什么？ 我看看
-What else you got in there? -Let's see....
教皇住在哪里？ 森林里
-Where does the Pope live? -ln the woods.
等等，那是开玩笑的
Wait,that's the joke answer.
他住在梵蒂冈
Actually,it's Vatican City.
你知道什么是硫化橡胶？
Now,what do you know about vulcanized rubber?
史波克（《星际迷航》）的节育用品
（史波克的星球充满硫磺味，乔伊以为有关系）
Spock's birth control.
你需要这套书
You need these books.
这里是你的旧房间？
This used to be your room?
你小时候一定很健美
You must have been in really good shape as a kid.
我真是个白痴
I'm such an idiot!
我居然以为她会改变
I can't believe I thought she could change.
谁管你妈妈怎么想？
Who cares what your mom thinks?
太莫妮卡了又怎样
So you "pulled a Monica."
这句话还真流行
I'm glad that's catching on.
谁说这一定要是坏话？ 去改变它的意义
Why does that have to be a bad thing? Just change what it means.
去证明你妈是错的
Prove your mother wrong.
你把工作顺利完成 我们就管它叫太莫妮卡了
You finish the job,and we'll call that "pulling a Monica."
什么？
What?
小孩每一科都拿A，父母会说 “你太莫妮卡了”
If a kid gets straight A's,his parents say,"You pulled a Monica."
消防员救出一个宝宝 大家会说“他太莫妮卡了”
A fireman saves a baby,and they go,"He pulled a Monica."
有人打全垒打，播报员会说 “这是一支好球”
Someone hits a homer,and they say,"That one's out of here."
当然有些事是不会变的
Because some things don't change.
好，我要下楼去
All right. I'll go down there.
我不上意大利面 我要上我做的菜
I won't serve the lasagna. I'll serve what I make.
我的咪咪真有力
My breasts are really strong.
钱德，拜托，我得把你铐回去 我的饭碗快不保了
I have to get you locked back up. I'm so going to lose my job!
她很在意办公室的隐私权
She's very private about her office!
我总算知道原因了
Now I know why!
你不管怎样都有麻烦
You're in trouble either way.
她看见我被铐在柜子上
If she sees me locked to this...
就会知道你进来过 你还不如让我走
...she'll know you were here. You might as well let me go.
我帮你洗浴室1个月 还是洗不干净
-I'll clean your bathroom for a month. -Still won't be clean.
我只要我的自由
All I want is my freedom.
揉脚1个月 自由
-Foot rubs for a month! -Freedom!
把你的相片通通整理好 自由，我要我的自由
-I'll put all your photos into albums! -I want my freedom!
你为什么不听 苏菲，救救我
Why won't you hear me! Sophie,help me!
苏菲，坐下
Sophie,sit!
自由
Freedom…
请你冷静好吗
Would you just calm down?!
我再说最后一次
I'm going to say this for the last time.
能不能请你…
Would you please just
我对呕吐的了解还真少
There's a lot I didn't know about vomit.
等一下
In a minute.
你觉得如何？
So what do you say?
1200元拥有整套百科全书
You get the whole set of encyclopedias for $1200.
平均一本才50元
That works out to just 50 bucks a book.
1200?
1200 dollas?
你觉得我有1200吗？
You think I have $1200?
我大白天窝在家里
I'm home during the day...
还把庭院的家具摆在起居室里
...and I got patio furniture in my living room.
有些事是书上学不到的
There's a few things you don't get from book learning.
你能凑出多少？
Well,what can you swing?
零首付，月付0元，永久期限如何？
How about zero down and zero a month for a long,long time?
你什么都没有？
You don't have anything?
你想看我有什么？好
You want to see what I got?
我有一个巧克力棒
I got a baby Tootsie Roll...
一张电影票根、钥匙、面纸
...a movie stub,keys,a Kleenex...
一块小石头
...a rock...
和一个玩具兵
...and an army man.
好，我懂了，耽误你时间了
Okay,I get the picture. Thanks for your time.
和50元
And a fifty.
这一定是钱德的裤子
These must be Chandler's pants.
50元可以买一本
For $50 you can get one book.
你要哪一本？A？B？C？
What will it be? A? B? C?
我还是买V好了
I'll stick with the V.
我想看看这个坏小孩结局如何
I want to see how this bad boy turns out.
我帮你买并且包装圣诞礼物 不要
I will buy and wrap all of your Christmas gifts!
我每天早上帮你榨柳橙汁
I'll squeeze you fresh orange juice every morning!
有果肉？ 有
-With extra pulp? -Yeah.
不要
No
我知道了
I've got it!
你不知道
You don't have it.
我完全知道了
I have so got it!
这件事会传出去，挡也挡不住
There will be rumors about this. No way to stop it.
苏菲知道 莫妮卡、菲比知道
Sophie,Monica and Phoebe know.
她们怎么会知道？ 我打给她们
-How do they know? -I called them.
当她们问我看到什么
When they ask me what I saw...
我可以很大方
...I can be very generous...
也可以很小气
...or very stingy.
说下去
Go on.
我可以让你成为传奇
I can make you a legend.
我可以让你成为现代的米尔顿・伯利（演员，传说他伟岸无比）
I can make you this generation's Milton Berle.
而米尔顿・伯利的… 根本比不上你
-And Milton Berle has -Not compared to you.
怎样？ 客人碰都没碰意大利面
They're not even touching the lasagna.
真的？ 他们好喜欢你的砂锅
They love your casserole!
漂亮
Yes！
不久前这些都还是材料呢
It's hard to believe a while ago this was just ingredients.
大家都很喜欢你做的菜
Everyone seems to like your dish.
那你呢？
And you?
我觉得…
I thought it was...
很好吃
...quite tasty.
要是大家都喜欢，你也喜欢
So if everyone liked it,and you liked it...
那就代表很成功，而你…
...that would make this a success. Which would make you....
就是恶婆娘？
A bitch?
我想说“你就错了” 但你的说法也行
I meant "wrong," but we can use your word.
对，我错了
Yes,well,I was wrong.
我必须要说
And I have to say...
你今天让我很感动
...you really impressed me today.
你还可以说她太莫妮卡了
You might even say that she "pulled a Monica."
她不知道我们改过了
She doesn't know we switched it.
下次你再帮我办宴会的时候
And the next time you cater for me...
冰箱里除了冰不会存别的东西
...there will be nothing but ice in the freezer.
这是很大的鼓励
That really means a lot.
妈，别咬指甲
Mom,don't bite your nails!
（中央咖啡馆）
钱德你好啊
Hello,Chandler.
我爱你
I love you.
怎么回事？
What's going on?
少来了
No,he doesn't!
持续了2小时
Two hours,that lasted.
所以你跟乔安娜分手了吗？
So did you break up with Joanna?
应该是吧
I think so.
幸好她像维苏威火山一样爆发之前 你就闪了
It's good you got out,before she blew up like Vesuvius.
火山？
The volcano?
对，讲到火山 那些火成岩还真暴力
Speaking of volcanoes,man,are they a violent igneous rock formation!
什么？ 熔岩乱喷，热灰乱飞
What?-Lava spewing,hot ash.
不过有些是休眠火山
Of course,some are dormant.
你怎么突然聊起火山来了？
Why are you talking about volcanoes all of a sudden?
不一定要聊火山（以V开头的）
We don't have to.
你们想聊什么？活体解剖（以V开头的）？
What do you want to talk about? Vivisection?
输精管（以V开头的）？
The vas deferens?
越战（以V开头的）？
The Vietnam War?
有人看那部韩战纪录片吗？ 有
Did anyone see that documentary on the Korean War?
韩国那么美
Korea's a beautiful country.
命运却好悲惨
With such a sad history.
有好多姓金的
Could there be more Kims?
外面是谁？ 是我，早安
-Who's out there? -Me! Good morning!
瑞秋，你能不能进来一下？
Could you come in here,please?
好 没有罂粟籽焙果了
Sure! They didn't have poppyseed bagels...
所以我买了芝麻的…天哪
...so I have sesame Oh,my word!
我出了一点办公室灾难
I've had a slight office mishap.
请把门后的钥匙拿给我 好
Could you get the key for me?
能不能请你… 对不起
-lf you could. -Oh,I'm sorry!
告诉你的朋友钱德 我们这次绝对是分手了
You can tell your friend Chandler we're definitely broken up this time!